RYAN DRAKE

Phone: 585.857.2164

Website: DrakeOpensource.github.io

Email: ryandrakecommunications@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/ryan-drake-58090620a/ GitHub: github.com/DrakeOpensource/Portfolio/

Address: Boston, MA 02130

Objective

I am a Google Certified Data Analyst with a diverse background and deep scientific skillset. I am seeking employment in data science or data analytics where someone with 3+ years of experience and who is passionate about data can excel.

Skills

Technical Skills

SQL, Python, Pandas, SciKit Learn, Tensorflow, Apache, R, React, Redux, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, node, Tableau, Microsoft Excel, SPSS

Publications

Janbatian H, Drake R, Melki S, Brenner J. The effect of low predicted/calculated postoperative keratometry on corrected distance visual acuity after LASIK. J Cataract Refract Surg. 2019 12; 45(12):1770 1776. PMID: 31856988.

General Skills

Exploratory Data Analysis, ETL, A/B Testing, Pattern and Trend Identification, Data Preparation, Data Analysis, Web Analytics, Visualization of Data Insights, Data Reports, Machine Learning

Soft Skills

Communication, Storytelling, Adaptability, Critical Thinking, Problem Solving, Troubleshooting, Business Sense, Curiosity, Collaboration

References

Charlene Ong, MD
Director, The Ong Lab
cjong@bu.edu
412.559.1769

Bryan Hoban
Director of Search Engine Optimization,
829 LLC
Bryan@829llc.com
781.422.4486

Relevant Work Experience

DATA SCIENTIST - EAST - Virginia, United States - 08/2021 - Current

- Non-profit dedicated to eliminating barriers to education in the STEM fields among incarcerated and formerly incarcerated learners
- Data analysis and design of courses and projects with interdisciplinary teams to achieve EAST OKRs

SENIOR PROJECT MANAGER - The Ong Lab - Boston, Massachusetts - 12/2019 - 6/2021

- Wrote and won a competitive national grant to perform a study on predicting stroke from heart disease
- Project lead and manager, AGILE workflow, coordinated data collaboration between groups
- · Executed ETL to congregate and standardize healthcare data from multiple hospital systems and international studies
- Completed statistical and ML driven analysis to achieve KPIs/OKRs

OPHTHALMIC AND SURGICAL TECHNICIAN - Boston Laser - Brookline, Massachusetts - 03/2017 - 12/2018

- Diverse roles: ophthalmic technician, surgical assistant, client operations, research
- Implemented changes to Rx prior authorization management, increased efficiency by 50%
- · Published original statistical research based on data that evidenced against a commonly held belief in refractive surgery

QUANTUM CHEMISTRY RESEARCH - The Velarde Lab - Buffalo, New York - 08/2014 - 06/2016

- Developed software (LabVIEW, C++) to interface optical devices, collect spectral data, and perform complex calculations
- Designed and implemented multifaceted research on Nano-particle interactions with cell membranes

Education

BOSTON UNIVERSITY SCHOOL OF MEDICINE - Medical Doctor MD - Boston, Massachusetts - 07/2018 - 02/2021
BOSTON UNIVERSITY SCHOOL OF MEDICINE - Medical Sciences MS - Boston, Massachusetts - 07/2016 - 06/2018

• Volunteered at the Outreach Van Project, a community outreach to provide food and medical assistance to the underserved

UNIVERSITY AT BUFFALO - Chemistry BA, Psychology BS - Boston, Massachusetts - 08/2011 - 06/2016

- Physical Chemistry and Neuropsychology Focus
- Presented research at the American Chemical Society on Nano-particle interactions
- Had research presented at a meeting of Principal Investigators sponsored by the U.S. Department of Energy